



Md Raufur Rahman

O Home: Mo 105/3 Merul Badda, 1212, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Email: raufurrahman777@gmail.com **\ Phone:** (+880) 1626217134

Website: https://raufurrahman.vercel.app/

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-raufur-rahman-03097a21a

Github: https://github.com/raufur-simanto

Gitlab: https://gitlab.com/RaufurRahman

Gender: Male Date of birth: 10/11/1998 Nationality: Bangladeshi

ABOUT ME

I'm Md Raufur Rahman, a software engineer experienced in backend development, cloud computing, and I design and implement scalable microservices using Python with frameworks like Flask. I am also experienced in artificial intelligence. My data science skills include extracting features and predicting results from complex datasets using machine learning, statistical analysis and video classification using computer vision. I am interested in Cloud, DevOps. I'm also interested in robotics. I am also highly motivated to go for higher studies in the field related to computer science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/01/2023 - Current] **Cloud Software Engineer**

InterCloud Limited https://intercloud.com.bd/

City: DHAKA

Name of unit or department: Brilliant Cloud

Business or sector: Information and communication

- Design and development of backend systems and services. This includes designing APIs and building micro services.
- · Integration of Cloud Services. Working with services like EC2, IAM, Notification, Load Balancer and more.
- Improvement of system performance and scalability
- Ensure the security of the system by implementing authentication and authorization.
- Monitoring and logging to detect issues and troubleshoot problems.
- Database Management
- Implement CI/CD pipelines to automate deployment

[15/01/2022 - 01/02/2022]

Industrial Attachment

BIIT Ltd

City: DHAKA

- App development with Java
- Created a basic application that records and displays the student's name, email address, and phone number after they are input.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[23/02/2017 - 12/09/2022]

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Chittagong University of Engineering and Technology https://cuet.ac.bd/

City: Chittagong

Field(s) of study: Computer Science and Engineering

Final grade: 3.45

Thesis: Umpire Gesture Recognition using Deep Learning Approach

- Programming
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Databases
- Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning
- Data Science
- Software Engineering
- Web Development
- Human-Computer Interaction(HCI)
- Computer Architecture
- Operating Systems
- Computer Networks
- Computer Graphics

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Bengali

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING C1 WRITING B1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Docker | Kubernetes | Jenkins | Confluence | Git | Jira | Linux | Scripting BashCMD (Base) | Graphana | MySql, Postgres, Redis, RabbitMq | Mongodb / Mongoose | API Python frameworks: Flask, FastAPI - Uvicorn | Async Workers (Celery, RQ) | Apache NGINX | Python | C++ | C | RestAPIs

PROBLEM SOLVING

LeetCode

Solve Approximately 250 problems.

Link: https://leetcode.com/Raufur/

Code Forces

Solve more than **300** problems and participates in online contests.

Max Rating-1396

Link: https://codeforces.com/profile/Raufur 7770/

PROJECTS

MicroBlog

It is a simple web application where user can create account, post something, send message to other user, follow or unfollow other user, can see other user's post, search user by their name or post. This project is built using python, flask, celery and deployed by docker, docker-compose

Link: https://gitlab.com/RaufurRahman/flask_work

Online Market

This is a simple web application where user can buy and sell product based on their credit. Python, Flask, Docker, Redis is user for this project. This application is then deployed in cloud platform

Link: https://gitlab.com/RaufurRahman/online market

Voice Assistant

Write here the descBuilt a desktop voice assistant which takes voice command and performs task according to it.Features are like top news of the day, search in wikipedia, open google, youtube, facebook, stackoverflow, open video.Implemented using Python, Pyttsx3, Speech Recognition.

Link: https://github.com/raufur-simanto/Voice-Assistant/tree/master

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Traveling

Sports

Reading